<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Félix González-Torres Project</title>
            <author xml:id="YourAuthorID" ref="YourAuthorURI">Robert Storr, Miwon Kwon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Steidl</publisher>
            <pubPlace>New York, USA</pubPlace>
            <availability>
               <p>Available by Purchase.</p>
               <date>2006</date>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         Contributor(s): Robert Storr, Robert Nickas, 
         Russell Ferguson, Lewis Baltz, Nancy Spector,
          Joseph Kosuth, Miwon Kwon, et al.
         <particDesc>
            <listPerson>
               <person xml:id="FGT" ref="https://www.felixgonzalez-torresfoundation.org/selected-monographs-and-solo-catalogues/felix-gonzalez-torres6">
                  <persName>Félix González-Torres</persName>
               </person>
            </listPerson>
         </particDesc>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="en">
      elix Gonzalez-Torres lived and worked resolutely according to 
      his own idealistic principles, combining elements of Conceptual
       art, Minimalism, political activism, and poetic beauty in an
        ever-expanding arsenal of media, including public billboards,
         give-away piles of candy and posters, and ordinary objects--
         clocks, mirrors, light fixtures--used to startling effect.
          His work challenged the notions of public and private space,
           originality, authorship and--most significantly--
           the authoritative structures in which he and his viewers 
           functioned. Editor Julie Ault has amassed the first 
           comprehensive monograph to span Gonzalez-Torres's career.
            In the spirit of his method, she rethinks the very idea 
            of what a monograph should be.
      <front>
         <div type="project-description">
            <p>The book, which places strong emphasis on the written word,
             contains newly commissioned texts by Robert Storr and
              Miwon Kwon, an introduction by Susan Cahill and an 
              extended conversation with fellow artist Tim Rollins, 
              as well as significant critical essays, exhibition statements,
               transcripts from lectures, personal correspondence, and 
               writings that influenced Gonzalez-Torres and his work.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         Félix González-Torres, hailing from Cuba, was a visionary artist whose works, 
            particularly poignant in the context of the AIDS epidemic, explored themes of
             identity and impermanence. Through minimalistic yet evocative creations, often
              employing everyday objects, he invited viewers to contemplate the transient nature of existence. 
              González-Torres, deeply affected by the AIDS crisis, infused his art with personal and political dimensions, 
              addressing issues of love, loss, and the passage of time. His thought-provoking pieces, 
              like the "Untitled" candy spills representing the AIDS pandemic's impact, continue to inspire discourse, 
              making him a pioneering figure in contemporary art.
         <div type="artwork">
            <head>Félix González-Torres Artwork</head>
            <p>Your description of a specific artwork by González-Torres.</p>
         </div>
         Félix González-Torres (1957-1996) was a renowned American artist
          known for conceptual and minimalist works. His art explored 
          themes of love, loss, and identity. Notable for his "candy spills" and 
          "stacks" of everyday objects, González-Torres invited viewer 
          participation, making art a shared experience. 
          His work transcends boundaries, leaving a profound, 
          emotional impact.
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
